A Finding Aid to the Francis V. O'Connor Papers, 1920-2009, in the Archives of American Art AAA.oconfran
Archives of American Art
Francis V. O'Connor papers
1920-2009
AAA.oconfran
Archives of American Art
23.4 Linear feet
The papers of New York art historian Francis O'Connor measure 23.4 linear feet and date from 1920-2009. Found within the papers are artist and exhibition files, questionnaires, transcripts, writings, project files, and printed material that pertain to O'Connor's research and publications on the New Deal and the Federal Arts Project of the Works Progress Administration.
O'Connor, Francis V.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers were donated by Francis O'Connor to the National Collection of Fine Arts, now the Smithsonian American Art Museum, which subsequently transferred the papers, with O'Connor's permission, to the Archives of American Art in 1974. In 2010, O'Connor donated an additional 15.8 linear feet of papers to the Archives.
Separated Materials note
Bound assemblies of periodicals were transferred to the Smithsonian Art Libraries in 2010, which retained relevant volumes and made final decisions regarding disposition of any remaining items.
Existence and Location of Copies note
About one-third of the collection (the "NCFA Library") is available on 35 mm microfilm reels 1084-1091 at the Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the papers as described in this finding aid does not reflect the order of the collection on microfilm due to reprocessing.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Use of archival audiovisual recordings and electronic media with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice. The Artists' Questionanaires require permission from each artist before publishing, quoting, or reproducing. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Biographical/Historical note
New York art historian and poet Francis O'Connor (1937- ) is best known for his research and writings on the New Deal art programs of the Depression and the Roosevelt Administration. O'Connor received his Ph. D. from Johns Hopkins University in 1965 and taught contemporary European and American art history at the University of Maryland from 1964 to 1970. While at Maryland, he organized the country's first comprehensive exhibition of New Deal art programs since their ending in 1943. From 1967 to 1968, he also headed a research program for the National Endowment for the Arts to analyze the effectiveness of New Deal art patronage, which eventually led to the publication of Federal Support for the Visual Arts: The New Deal and Now (1969), New Deal Art Projects: An Anthology of Memoirs (1972), Art for the Millions (1973).
In addition to his work on New Deal art patronage, throughout the 1980s and 1990s, O'Connor continued to teach and lecture at universities, consulted on federally and privately funded research projects, and published critical essays for exhibition catalogs, anthologies and academic journals. He is a member of the College Art Association, International Association of Art Critics, and founded the Association of Independent Historians of Art in 1982.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of New York art historian Francis O'Connor measure 23.4 linear feet and date from 1920-2009. Found within the papers are artist and exhibition files, questionnaires, transcripts, writings, project files, and printed material that pertain to O'Connor's research and publications on the New Deal and the Federal Arts Project of the Works Progress Administration.
The "NCFA Library" consists of research materials collected, created, and compiled during the course of O'Connor's research project supported by the National Endowment for the Humanities for his books Federal Support for the Visual Arts (1969) and Art for the Millions (1973). Files contain administrative records, artists' files, and questionnaires and essays that document the administration of New Deal art projects. The files were collated by O'Connor into a set that remains intact.
The publications series consists of additional research and administrative materials specifically related to O'Connor's four publications on the WPA/FAP and New Deal artists: Federal Support for the Visual Arts: The New Deal and Now (1969), New Deal Art Projects: An Anthology of Memoirs (1972), Art for the Millions (1973), and Federal Art Patronage Notes (newsletter, 1974-1984).
New Deal research files are more general research materials collected by or sent to O'Connor in the course of his academic career. These include information on New Deal administrators and state specific WPA projects; photocopies of original WPA activity and reports; and New Deal scholarship, academic symposia, and conferences.
New Deal exhibitions include announcement and catalogs of contemporary New Deal art exhibitions in the U.S. from the 1960s to the 1990s. Project files are related to three publically and privately funded New Deal research projects O'Connor directed or participated in. Printed materials consists of press coverage of federal arts patronage in the United States dating from the 1960s to 2008.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 6 series. There is some overlap in series reflecting O'Connor's original order.
Series 1: NCFA Library, 1920-1974 (6.7 linear feet; Boxes 1-7, OV 28)
Series 2: Publications, 1939-1985 (4.3 linear feet; Boxes 7-11, BV 25-26, OV 27)
Series 3: New Deal Research Files, 1930-2009 (5.6 linear feet; Boxes 11-16)
Series 4: New Deal Exhibitions, 1961-1997 (1.4 linear feet; Boxes 17-18)
Series 5: Project Files, 1935-1999 (2 linear feet; Boxes 18-20)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1963-2008 (3.4 linear feet; Boxes 20-24)
Federal Art Project; National Endowment for the Arts; United States. Work Projects Administration.; United States. Works Progress Administration.; Art historians; Federal aid to the arts; New Deal, 1933-1939; Transcripts
- NCFA Library, 1920-1973; Series 1; 6.7 Linear feet Boxes 1-7, OV 28
  Scope and Contents note
  These materials comprise primary source documentation covering the administration of the WPA/FAP (Works Progress Administration/Federal Arts Project) and its activities in New York City and State collected or created during O'Connor's National Endowment for the Humanities' sponsored research project, Federal Support for the Visual Arts (1969), and his subsequent book, Art for the Millions (1973).
  Arrangement note
  The series is arranged as 4 subseries. Materials retain O'Connor's original folder headings and arrangement and were compiled as a distinct set of research materials for the National Collection of Fine Arts Libary. There is some overlap with Series 2.
  1.1: WPA/FAP NY Administrative Records, 1935-1969
  1.2: WPA/FAP Artists' Files, 1936-1971
  1.3: GSA Artists' Employment History Records, 1936-1973
  1.4: WPA Artists' Essays, 1920-1965
  - WPA/FAP New York Administrative Records, 1935-1969; 1.1
    Administrative records consist of photocopies of documents selected from the original records of the New York WPA/FAP at the National Archives. Documents relating to the early administration of the WPA/FAP in New York (1935) are filed at the beginning of the series. All other folder headings in the series begin with January, 1936. This series includes office administrative and employee files; program policies and procedures; and artist, project, and exhibition files. O'Connor's original research notations, correspondence, and writings have also been retained within the records.
    - Handbook to New Deal Art Project Materials in the Library of the National Collection of Fine Arts, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1935 Documents (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - General Subjects, Advisory Committee, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General Subjects, Alaska Project, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - General Subjects, Art and Psychotherapy, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - General Subjects, Artists Groups, circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - General Subjects, C.C.C. and WPA/FAP, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - General Subjects, "Communism" Problem, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - General Subjects, "Communism" Problem, Ralph M. Easley Correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - General Subjects, Congressional Relations, H.R. Sub-Committee on Appropriations, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - General Subjects, Criticism of Project Art, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - General Subjects, Municipal Art Commission and WPA/FAP, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - General Subjects, Municipal Art Commission, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - General Subjects, Museum of Modern Art, 1938-1942 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - General Subjects, Project Requests and Proposals, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - General Subjects, Public Use of Arts Committee, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - General Subjects, Relationship of Blacks to the NY WPA/FAP, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - General Subjects, Technical Bulletins, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - General Subjects, Technical Commissions, Artists' Oil Paints, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - General Subjects, "Technique" Films (of artists), 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - General Subjects, War and Defense Efforts, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Administration, Procedures, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Administration, Supervisory Personnel, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Administration, Cahill, Holger, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Administration, McMahon, Audrey, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Administration, Somervell, Brehon, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Administration, Stein, Harold, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Administration, Funding and Budget Problems, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Administration, National Survey of WPA/FAP, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Administration, Organization Charts, 1935-1940 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Oversized material housed in OV 28.
    - Administration, Physical Plant, NYC, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Administration, Quality of Art Produced, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Administration, Sponsorship Procedures, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Administration, 1939 Changeover, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Administration, 1943 Liquidation (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Administration, After 1943 Liquidation, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Allocations, Policy and Procedures, 1936-1942 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Allocations, Dispute of Work to Federal Government, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Allocations, Museum Problem, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Allocations, Lists, circa 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Artists, Biographical Material and Cross References, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Artists, Transferred from TRAP to FAP, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Artists, Awards and Honors, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Community Art Centers, NYC, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Community Art Centers, Harlem, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Employment, Policy and Procedures, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Employment, Quotas, Figures and Policy, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Employment, Loan Artists, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Employment, Quota Adjustments for Transferral of TRAP Artists to FAP, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 50-51)
    - Exhibitions, General, 1936-1942 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Exhibitions, Policy and Procedures, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Exhibitions, Director, Halpert, Edith, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Exhibitions, New Horizons in American Art (1936) (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Exhibitions, de Young Museum Show, circa 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Exhibitions, Federal Art Galleries, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Exhibitions, Index of American Design, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Exhibitions, Phillips Gallery Show, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Federal Project No. 1, Transfer of Four Arts Projects from Federal to City Control, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Federal Project No. 1, Establishment, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Federal Project No. 1, Administrative Officer, Edwards, Paul, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Federal Project No. 1, Music Project, circa 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Federal Project No. 1, NYC/FAP, Music Project, circa 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Federal Project No. 1, Theatre Project, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Federal Project No. 1, NYC/FAP, Theatre Project, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Federal Project No. 1, Writers Project, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Federal Project No. 1, NYC/FAP, Writers Project, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Project Divisions, Easel, 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Project Divisions, Mural, 1936-1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Project Divisions, Graphic, 1936-1941 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Project Divisions, Sculpture, 1936-1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Project Divisions, Art Teaching, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Project Divisions, Design Laboratory, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Project Divisions, Photography, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Project Divisions, Poster, 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Project Divisions, NYC/FAP Section of Painting and Sculpture, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Index of American Design, Administration and Personnel, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Index of American Design, Manual and Research, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Index of American Design, Inventory of Material, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Index of American Design, New York State, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Labor Relations, Policy, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Labor Relations, Appeal Procedures, 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Labor Relations, Classification of Artists, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Labor Relations, Demonstrations and Sit-Ins, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Labor Relations, Dismissal Problems, 1936-1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Labor Relations, Non-Relief Quota Problem, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Labor Relations, Petitions, 1936-1942 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Labor Relations, Requests for Employment, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Labor Relations, Sick Leave and Holidays, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Labor Relations, Timekeeping Problems, 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Labor Relations, Union Influence on Project Division Operations, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Labor Relations, Wage Rates, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Labor Relations, Welfare Department Procedures, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Labor Relations, November 1st Ruling, 1935, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Labor Relations, March 6th Ruling, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Labor Relations, November 1936 Protests (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Labor Relations, 25% Cutback, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Labor Relations, Alien Rule, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Labor Relations, $1000 Per Artist Proposal, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Labor Relations, 10% Increase Demands, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Labor Relations, Fernand Leger Problem, circa 1935 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Labor Relations, Artists Project Workers, Popper, Martin, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Labor Relations, Director of Labor Relations, Ryan, Charles (case), 1938 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Labor Relations, Artists' Congress, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Labor Relations, Artists' Union, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Labor Relations, Other Artists' Committees, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - NY State FAP, Cumulative Monthly Progress Reports, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - NY State FAP, West Point/Woodstock Projects, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - NY State FAP, New Jersey FAP, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Publicity, Policies and Procedures, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Publicity, Press Coverage, 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Publicity, Lectures and Speeches, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Publicity, Sunday Night Art Forums, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Treasury Projects, Administrative Policies and Procedures, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Miscellaneous, Defense Work, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous, World's Fair, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Miscellaneous, Summaries of Activities and Accomplishments, circa 1940 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Miscellaneous, Statements of Support for FAP, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Miscellaneous, Travel Vouchers, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Miscellaneous, WPA, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Miscellaneous, Non-Art, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Oversized Organization Charts from Box 1, Folder 31, 1935-1940 (Box OV 28)
  - WPA/FAP Artists' Files, 1936-1971; 1.2
    Files consist of questionnaires filled out by WPA, PWAP (Public Works of Art Project), Treasury Section, and TRAP (Treasury Relief Art Project) artists for O'Connor's Federal Support for the Visual Arts: The New Deal and Now project (FSVA) dating from 1967-1969. Included in some artists' files are original artist correspondence, curriculum vitae, exhibition catalogs, and announcements. Also found are copies of WPA correspondence from the National Archives, and copies of Government Service Administration employment histories. Original research notations, and two reports drafted by O'Connor are retained within the records. Statistical data derived from the questionnaires are included in the reports.
    - Report on the New Deal Art Projects in NYC and State with Recommendations for Present-Day Federal Support for the Visual Arts, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Profile of the WPA Federal Art Project Artist in New York with Questionnaire Coding Guides, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Artists' Statements, circa 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Analysis of Employment Transcript Data, circa 1968 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Abbott, Berenice, 1936-1968 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Abelman, Ida, 1938-1968 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Ajay, Abraham, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Angell (Angel), Rifka, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Annino, Louis, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Arnold, Grant, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Avery, Frances, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Barber, John, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Barile, Xavier J., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Barnet, Will, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Barr, Norman, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Baum, Max, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Baumbach, Harold, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Beach, Sarah Berman, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bell, Cecil C., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Bell, Clara L., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Berman, Saul, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Blanche, Arnold, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Block, Irving, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Block, Louis, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Bodin, Paul, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Brooks, James D., circa 1940-1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Brown, Rosalind Bengelsdorf, 1938-1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Buzzelli, Joseph Anthony, 1938-1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Chanase, Dane, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Cheney, Philip, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Citron, Minna, 1938-1968 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Cohn, Max Arthur, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Cole, Thomas C., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Constant, George, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Cornin, Jon, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Crampton, Rollin M., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Cronbach, Robert M., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Csoka, Stephen, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - D'Agostino, Vincent, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Datz, Mark, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Dehn, Adolf A., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Dobkin, Alexander, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Edie, Stuart, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Edwards, Emmett, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Egri, Theodore, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Eichenberg, Fritz, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Emerson, Sybil, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Esman, Betty, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Evergood, Philip, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Fairchild, Elizabeth, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Farruggio, Remo, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Fasano, Clara, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Fastovsky, Aaron, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Fein, Stanley, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Floethe, Richard, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Fruhauf, Aline, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Gasparo, Oronzo, 1962-1970 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Gershoy, Eugenie, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Glannon, Edward J., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Glen, John S., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Goff, Lloyd L., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Goodelman, Aaron J., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Gottlieb, Adolph, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Greco, Frank, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Greenwood, Marion K., 1940-1968 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Gregory, John, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Gropper, William, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Gross, Chaim, 1937-1968 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Grunvald, Samuel, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Gubin, Selma, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Gunn, Arthur, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Gutieri, Ralph, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Guy, James, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Harris, Louis, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Haupt, Theodore, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Helfond, Riva, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Hios, Theodore, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Hoffman, Irwin D., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Houdius, Gerrit, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Janowsky, Bela, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Johnson, Philip, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Kainen, Jacob, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Kaplan, Joseph, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Kassoy, Bernard, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Kelpe, Paul, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - King, Roy E., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Knight, Frederick, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Konzal, Joseph, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Krassner, Lenore, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Kruckman, Herbert, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Kudish, Aaron, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - La More, Chet, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Lane, Harry, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Lassaw, Ibram, 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Lassen, Ben, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Laufman, Sidney, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Lehman, Irving, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Lewis, Norman, 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Limbach, Russel T., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Lipkin, Jacob, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Loew, Michael, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Lozowick, Louis, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Lubin, Jacob, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - MacCoy, Guy, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Marantz, Irving, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Margo, Boris, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Margolis, David, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Matulka, Jan, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Maunsbach, Eric, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - McEvoy, Myrtle, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Neagoe, Anne, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Neel, Alice, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Neuwirth, Morris, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Nevelson, Louise, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - New, Babette, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Nickerson, Ruth, 1940-1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Olds, Elizabeth, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Opper, John, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Palmer, William C., 1960-1968 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Parrish, Betty, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Penney, James, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Perelli, Victor, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Picken, George, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Pont, Charles E., 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Powell, Leslie, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)